Finding Aid for the Robert Hardy Andrews Papers LSC.0812
UCLA Library Special Collections
Robert Hardy Andrews papers
1945-1966
UCLA Library Special Collections
Andrews, Robert Hardy
LSC.0812
2.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Robert Hardy Andrews (b.1908) was a reporter, then city editor for Minneapolis journal and later of "Midweek" for the Chicago daily news. He was also a writer-producer for radio, motion pictures and television, author of books, screenplays, television scripts and short stories. The collection consists of literary manuscripts, movie and television scripts, newspaper columns, and ephemera related to Andrews' career and writings.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Hardy Andrews, 1963 and 1967.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994622013606533
Biography
Born as Charles Robert Douglas Hardy Andrews on October 19, 1908 in Effingham, Kansas; attended University of Minnesota, Northwestern, University of Chicago; reporter, then city editor for Minneapolis journal and later of "Midweek" for the Chicago daily news; writer-producer for radio, motion pictures, and television; author of books, screenplays, television scripts, and short stories; film production executive in India and Egypt; consultant to U.S. firms in the Far East.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of literary manuscripts, movie and television scripts, newspaper columns, and ephemera related to the career and writings of Robert Hardy Andrews.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Burning gold typescript (Box 1).
Corner of Chicago typescript and ephemera (Boxes 2 & 4).
Movie and television scripts; A lamp for India (Box 3).
Related Material
Robert Douglas Andrews Papers, 1930-1968 (ca. 300 items). Available at Boston University Libraries. Additions to this collection are anticipated.
Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Journalists -- United States -- Archives.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Andrews, Robert Hardy -- Archives
- Burning Gold. n.p., undated.; Andrews, Robert Hardy; (1008 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  A novel first published by Doubleday, Doran and Company, Garden City, New York, 1945.
- Another copy., (408 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1)
- A Corner of Chicago. Ojai, California, 1962.; (424 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 2)
  First published by Little, Brown, and Company, Boston, 1963.
  Some correspondence relating to the publishing of "A Corner of Chicago" is bound in at the end.
- Another copy. Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1963.; (121 leaves, galleys) (Box 2)
- First draft. Ojai, California, 1962.; (31 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 2)
- Ephemera relating to "A Corner of Chicago.", (2 items) (Box 2)
- Letter to Andrews from James T. Farrell. Chicago, December 11, 1961.; (14 leaves, holograph and photocopy) (Box 2)
  General note
  Original withdrawn by donor (December 1968).
- Movie and television scripts., Scripts for: Ford Theatre; Thriller; Combat; Death Valley Days and Adventures of Don Renegale. (Box 3)
- A lamp for India: the story of Madame Pandit. [Beverly Hills, California, ]., ca. 1966; (ca. 500 leaves, typescript) (Box 3)
  With many changes and additions.
- [originally titled, "Of Victory and Fortune"]. Beverly Hills, California, ca. 1966.; (ca. 400 leaves, typescript with changes and corrections) (Box 3)
  "Working Outline."
- A corner of Chicago. Ojai, California, ca. 1961.; (424 leaves, typescript carbon with many corrections) (Box 4)
  Apparently this was the printer's copy.
- Letter to Andrews from James T. Farrell. Chicago, December 22, 1961.; (22 leaves, holograph on yellow legal-size paper and photocopy) (Box 4)
  Original withdrawn by donor (January 1969).